boss.info 2019-12-03

# Roland - Privacy Statement

### ABOUT THE PROTECTION OF PERSONAL INFORMATION

Roland Corporation recognizes the importance of protecting the privacy of all information provided by users of this website. We created the following policy guidelines with a fundamental respect for our users’ right to privacy and because we value our relationships with our users.

Roland Corporation and its group companies (hereinafter referred to collectively as "We") may ask you to register your personal information, including your name, address, telephone number, and e-mail address, when conducting online surveys, signing up for membership sites, distributing e-mail newsletters, submitting applications for events and contests, registering products, and inquiring about product support, and we recognize that it is our social responsibility to protect such personal information.

We retain personal data and any information concerning this Privacy Policy on servers located in Japan and the U.S. managed by Roland Headquarters (personal information of users outside of Japan will be managed on the server located in Japan). Please note that this Privacy Policy is exclusively governed by Japanese law. By submitting your personal information to us, you understand and agree to accept the terms of this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree with the terms of this Privacy Policy, then please refrain from using this website and do not provide your personal information to us.

Roland Corporation uses reasonable precautions to keep the personal information disclosed to us secure. To prevent unauthorized access, maintain data accuracy, and ensure the correct use of information, we have put in place appropriate physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online from our users. Nevertheless, Roland Corporation does not guarantee the security, accuracy or completeness of any such information or procedures. Our protection of personal information is based on the following principles.

* * *

#### 1\. We use it only for the stated purposes

We always limit our use of personal information to within the range of purposes as provided below. When we need to use personal information beyond the range of the stated purposes, we will inform you of the new purposes in advance. If you cannot agree to the new purposes, you can deny permission for us to use your personal information.

_Purposes of use_

  1. Provision of membership sites 
    * To identify the membership registration applicant, members, and service users
    * To authenticate the user when using the service
  2. Provision of a variety of information by e-mails and direct mail 
    * To offer information related to products and services of the Company and group companies (including promotion and advertising) and event information
    * To offer information related to products and services of the third parties that have been commissioned by the Company to send information (including promotion and advertising) and event information
    * To notify and inform registered users about other information
  3. Customer Support 
    * To receive and correspond with inquiries and consultation from users
    * To provide after-sales services, such as version updates, to users
    * To dispatch repaired products back to users
  4. Marketing (to plan, develop and improve products and services) 
    * To understand user registration status and usage conditions of membership sites
    * To conduct questionnaires/surveys and monitor surveys
  5. Other 
    * To notify changes of the purposes of use of the personal information and obtain consent
    * Otherwise, to be used in the range of consent separately provided by the member

* * *

#### 2\. We will not disclose personal information to third parties

We will not disclose the personal information you submit to us to any third parties except as provided below, and as described in section 4 below.

  * When you agree to such disclosure
  * When we, under strict company management, disclose personal information to such companies with which we have an advance agreement to delegate the task of processing personal information
  * When it is considered to be appropriate in order to enable a related company or distributor to respond to your inquiry
  * When we are required to disclose or provide personal information based on a law or regulation
  * When disclosure is needed to protect human health or safety or assets, and it is difficult to obtain your prior consent
  * When we need to cooperate with national or local governments in their official duties, and obtaining your consent may hinder those efforts

* * *

#### 3\. We will not transfer personal information overseas

We shall not transfer the personal information you submit to us to an overseas location, except as provided below or for shared use within overseas group companies as mentioned in the next section.

  * When you agree to such transfer
  * If the third party’s country is recognized by the rules of the Personal Information Protection Committee as being a foreign country that has an equivalent level of protection of personal information as our country, in order to protect the rights and interests of individuals
  * When providing the personal information to any person who has established a system that complies with the standards set forth under the rules of the Personal Information Protection Committee as a system that is necessary in order to take measures, on a continuous basis, that correspond to the measures which should be taken by a business operator handling personal information with respect to the handling of personal data
  * When we are required to disclose or provide the personal information based on a law or regulation
  * When disclosure is needed to protect human health or safety or assets, and it is difficult to obtain your prior consent
  * When we need to cooperate with national or local governments in their official duties and obtaining your consent may hinder those efforts

* * *

#### 4\. We may share personal information

We may share your personal information with any of the following group companies.

_Personal-information items to be shared_

  * Your name, address, telephone number, fax number, e-mail address, Roland-issued ID number, products you have registered, etc.

_Parties who can share the personal information_

  * Roland Corporation U.S., Roland Europe Group and other overseas Group companies *1

*1: overseas group companies: Factory and Office Affiliates

_Purposes of use by those parties_

  * Customer Support
  * Marketing (to plan, develop and improve products and services)
  * Provision of a variety of information by e-mails and direct mails
  * Conducting various surveys

* * *

#### 5\. About cookies

A “cookie” is a small piece of data transmitted from a web server and stored on your computer. Although our web server can identify your computer by using a cookie, this allows you to efficiently access our web pages, and we shall not use it for any other purpose.

You can reject cookies from being stored on your computer via your computer’s browser settings, but please be aware that, in such case, the functions of our website may be partially limited for you.

In addition, in order to deliver the best advertising to customers, we use behavioral targeting advertising services provided by the following companies using cookies. If you want to disable this service, access the company's page provided below and follow the instructions.

  1. Google, Inc.  You can opt-out from the following site:  
<http://www.google.co.jp/intl/ja/policies/privacy/ads/>
  2. Yahoo Japan Corporation  
You can opt-out from the following site:  
<http://btoptout.yahoo.co.jp/optout/index.html>
  3. Facebook, Inc.  
You can opt-out from the following site:  
<https://www.facebook.com/ads/website_custom_audiences/>

* * *

#### 6\. About access logs

Our website records contain information on the people who have accessed it in an access log, as described herein:

The access log includes the IP address, domain name, browser, access date/time, etc., of those people accessing our website. We shall not use these access logs for the purpose of collecting personal information, nor shall we use them in combination with any information which may identify an individual.

We shall inform you of each purpose of using your access logs combined with your personal information when we use them for any purpose except as provided below:

  * Responding to inquiries that occur when you use our services
  * Creating statistical data, which do not identify individuals

* * *

#### 7\. Tracking system

A tracking system based on the use of our company cookies is employed in Roland's websites which gather IP address, access date/time, etc. We shall not use them in combination with any information which may identify an individual, beyond what is stated on the "Purposes of Use" on the upper section (1. We use it only for the stated purposes) of this privacy statement .

Also there is a tracking system based on the use of third-party cookies is employed in parts of Roland's websites in order to gather anonymous statistical information which is not linked to specific personal information.

We recommend that you regularly check our online Policies on the Protection of Personal Information because we may modify the policies in order to further enhance our protection of personal information or in accordance with changes to laws or regulations.

If you would like to update or decline to submit your personal information, please inform us from here*1. If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, or the terms of this site, please inform us from here*1.

*1 [Roland Account Service | Contact Us](https://account.roland.com/login/ "Roland Account Service | Contact Us")

Please also read our Policies on the Protection of Personal Information.

* * *

#### 8\. Personal information correction

If we are informed by users that their personal information is inaccurate, and are asked to modify, add, or delete data, we will investigate and, on the basis of the result, make the necessary adjustments without delay.

* * *

### ABOUT THE PROTECTION OF PERSONAL DATA FOR GDPR

Roland Corporation recognizes the importance of protecting the privacy of all information provided by users of this website. We created the following policy guidelines to be in compliance with the EU General Data Protection Regulation (hereinafter referred to as “GDPR”) when we process personal data of those who reside in European Economic Area (hereinafter referred to as “EEA”).

Roland Corporation (hereinafter referred to collectively as "We") may ask you to register your personal data, including your name, address, telephone number, and e-mail address, when conducting online surveys, signing up for membership sites, distributing e-mail newsletters, submitting applications for events and contests, registering products, and inquiring about product support, and we recognize that it is our social responsibility to protect such personal data.

We retain personal data and any information concerning this Privacy Policy on servers located in Japan or the U.S. managed by Roland Headquarters. By submitting your personal data to us, you understand and agree to accept the terms of this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree with the terms of this Privacy Policy, then please refrain from using this website and do not provide your personal data to us.

* * *

#### 1\. GDPR applies to following cases

With regard to our processing of personal data, GDPR applies to the following cases.

  * Where we process personal data which is collected directly from users, not being transferred from our European subsidiaries, through provision of products and services within EEA
  * Where we process personal data which is transferred to us from our subsidiaries or any other third party located in EEA

* * *

#### 2\. We collect following categories of personal data

We may collect the following categories of personal data for the purpose stated in this Privacy Policy.

  * Name
  * E-mail address
  * Sex
  * Country of residence

* * *

#### 3\. We process personal data based on stated legal basis and only for the stated purposes 

We always limit our use of personal data to within the range of purposes as provided below. When we need to use personal data beyond the range of the stated purposes, we will inform you of the new purposes in advance. If you cannot agree to the new purposes, you can deny permission for us to use your personal data. We also process your personal data based on the legal basis provided below.

_Purposes of use_

  1. Provision of membership sites 
    * To identify the membership registration applicant, members, and service users:   
This is necessary for performance of contract
    * To authenticate the user when using the service:   
This is necessary for performance of contract
  2. Provision of a variety of information by e-mails and direct mail 
    * To offer information related to products and services of the Company and group companies (including promotion and advertising) and event information:   
This is based on our legitimate interest of providing a professional services business
    * To offer information related to products and services of the third parties that have been commissioned by the Company to send information (including promotion and advertising) and event information:   
This is based on our legitimate interest of providing a professional services business
    * To notify and inform registered users about other information:   
This is necessary for performance of contract
  3. Customer Support 
    * To receive and correspond with inquiries and consultation from users:   
This is necessary for performance of contract
    * To provide after-sales services, such as version updates, to users:   
This is necessary for performance of contract
    * To dispatch repaired products back to users:   
This is necessary for performance of contract
  4. Marketing (to plan, develop and improve products and services) 
    * To understand user registration status and usage conditions of membership sites:   
This is based on our legitimate interest of providing a professional services business
    * To conduct questionnaires/surveys and monitor surveys:   
This is based on our legitimate interest of providing a professional services business
  5. Other 
    * To notify changes of the purposes of use of the personal data and obtain consent:   
This may be necessary for performance of contract or based on our legitimate interest of providing a professional services business
    * Otherwise, to be used in the range of consent separately provided by the member:   
This is subject to your continued consent

* * *

#### 4\. You have following rights

You have the following rights regarding personal data obtained and processed by us.

  * Obtaining information regarding processing of data  
You have the right to obtain from us all the requisite information regarding our data processing activities that concern you
  * Access to personal data  
You have the right to obtain from us confirmation as to whether personal data concerning you are being processes, and if so, then access to the personal data and certain related information.
  * Rectification or erasure of personal data  
You have the right to have us rectify inaccurate personal data concerning you without undue delay and the right to have us complete any incomplete personal data. Also, if certain conditions are satisfied, you will have the right to have us delete personal data concerning you without undue delay.
  * Restriction on processing of personal data  
If certain conditions are satisfied, you will have the right to have us restricted processing of personal data concerning you.
  * Objection to processing of personal data  
If certain conditions are satisfied, you will have the right to object to processing of personal data concerning you. 
  * Data portability of personal data  
If certain conditions are satisfied, you will have the right to receive personal data concerning you in a structured, commonly used, and machine-readable format and the right to transfer those data to another controller without hindrance from us. 
  * Not to be subject to automated decision-making  
If certain conditions are satisfied, you will have the right not to be subject to solely data-based, automated decision-making(including profiling) that produces any legal or similar material effect on you. 
  * Not to be subject to direct marketing  
You have the right to object at any time to processing of personal data concerning you for direct marketing. 
  * Withdraw your consent  
You have the right to withdraw your consent at any time. The withdrawal will not affect the lawfulness of processing based on consent before its withdrawal.
  * Lodge a complaint  
You have the right to lodge a complaint in relation to our processing of your personal data with a supervisory authority in EEA

If you intend to exercise any of the aforementioned rights, please inquire from here*1.

*1 [Roland Account Service | Contact Us](https://account.roland.com/login/ "Roland Account Service | Contact Us")

* * *

#### 5\. We keep your personal data secure

We process in a manner that ensures appropriate security of the personal data by using appropriate technical and organizational measures.

* * *

#### 6\. Child under age of 16 needs parental consent

For child below age of 16, please have consent by the holder of parental responsibility over you before you submit your personal data to us. 

* * *

#### 7\. We will not disclose nor transfer personal data to third parties

We will not disclose nor transfer the personal data concerning you to any third parties except as provided below.

  * When we share the use within overseas group companies within the scope of the purpose stated in this Privacy Policy *1 

*1: overseas group companies: Factory and Office Affiliates

  * When you agree to such disclosure or transfer
  * When we, under strict company management, disclose personal data to such companies with which we have an advance agreement to delegate the task of processing personal data
  * When it is considered to be appropriate in order to enable a related company or distributor to respond to your inquiry
  * When it is allowed under GDPR

* * *

#### 8\. We may transfer personal data to third countries outside of EEA

At the disclosure or transfer of personal data stated in the above section7, we may transfer the personal data you submit to us to a third party outside of EEA. This includes overseas group companies and processor. We exercise adequate and appropriate supervision over such third party to take appropriate safeguard based on GDPR as to the situation of transfer.

* * *

#### 9\. About cookies

A “cookie” is a small piece of data transmitted from a web server and stored on your computer. Although our web server can identify your computer by using a cookie, this allows you to efficiently access our web pages, and we shall not use it for any other purpose.

You can reject cookies from being stored on your computer via your computer’s browser settings, but please be aware that, in such case, the functions of our website may be partially limited for you.

In addition, in order to deliver the best advertising to customers, we use behavioral targeting advertising services provided by the following companies using cookies. If you want to disable this service, access the company's page provided below and follow the instructions.

  1. Google, Inc.   
You can opt-out from the following site:  
<http://www.google.co.jp/intl/ja/policies/privacy/ads/>
  2. Yahoo Japan Corporation  
You can opt-out from the following site:  
<http://btoptout.yahoo.co.jp/optout/index.html>
  3. Facebook, Inc.  
You can opt-out from the following site:  
<https://www.facebook.com/ads/website_custom_audiences/>

* * *

#### 10\. About access logs

Our website records contain information on the people who have accessed it in an access log, as described herein:

The access log includes the IP address, domain name, browser, access date/time, etc., of those people accessing our website. We shall not use these access logs for the purpose of collecting personal data, nor shall we use them in combination with any information which may identify an individual.

We shall inform you of each purpose of using your access logs combined with your personal data when we use them for any purpose except as provided below:

  * Responding to inquiries that occur when you use our services
  * Creating statistical data, which do not identify individuals

* * *

#### 11\. About Tracking system

A tracking system based on the use of our company cookies is employed in Roland's websites which gather IP address, access date/time, etc. We shall not use them in combination with any information which may identify an individual, beyond what is stated on the "Purposes of Use" on the upper section (3. We process personal data based on stated legal basis and only for the stated purposes) of this Privacy Policy.

Also there is a tracking system based on the use of third-party cookies employed in parts of Roland's websites in order to gather anonymous statistical information which is not linked to specific personal data.

* * *

#### 12\. We retain personal data for certain period

We will retain your personal data for as long as necessary to fulfill the aforementioned "Purposes of Use" on the upper section (3. We process personal data based on stated legal basis and only for the stated purposes). We will delete your personal data promptly when it becomes unnecessary for us to retain.

* * *

#### 13\. We may amend this Privacy Policy

We review and amend this Privacy Policy time to time for improvement.

* * *

#### 14\. You can reach us

For questions or inquiries regarding this Privacy Policy, please contact the data controller or representative set out below.

Data Controller:  
Roland Corporation  
2036-1 Nakagawa, Hosoe-cho, Kita-ku, Hamamatsu, Shizuoka 431-1304, Japan  

Representative:  
Roland Europe Group Ltd.  
Hive 2 1530, Arlington Business Park, Theale, Reading, Berkshire, RG7 4SA, UK  
REG-DPO@roland.com
